now we are going to look at some of the
other t-box modules which could be
useful when you are working with
different process or you want to do some
performance checks the first is the
process operations and part of this you
have the Start program which is a t-box
module so using this you can start any
particular application be it a exe a
desktop application or even a browser
okay so let's go ahead and look at this
let me create open
or a Start program right
so let's create a new folder here and
I'm going to call it process operations
inside this let me create another test
case and let's call it open
[Music]
notepad Okay so this is the application
which I want to open to Tosca
and let's see how we can do that so
let's go ahead and add the t-box module
now
and we'll say open
or Start program
okay and here we have to give some
parameters for notepad.exe we just
require the path
okay so I'm going to give the path here
which is C window
and notepad.exe
okay uh similarly you can pass the path
for any particular application
um you can also pass arguments
um and wait for exit and also run as
which will have the username and
password if uh it's a secure application
right so these are all the different
parameters which you can pass you can
use whichever application you require
okay
but for us it is notepad.exe so let's go
ahead and run this
as you can see the step has passed and
in the background uh Tosca has opened a
Notepad application or the notepad.exe
right so that's what uh how you can
start a particular program or
application uh using Oscar okay using
the steebok Start program module
to show another example out of it right
um I can also add another devox module
here
so
and this time around we are going to
open uh the Chrome browser okay with
some parameters so let's go ahead and
browse the Chrome browser okay
and that you will find here in C program
files Google Chrome application okay if
it's a 64-bit if it's uh not a 64-bit
you will find it in the x86 folder
so here I have got the chrome.exe so I'm
going to browse to that path right and
then um
I will also add some arguments okay so
inside the arguments
uh I'm going to first add a argument for
Incognito because I want to start this
browser in in computer mode
and then I'm going to pass the URL which
it should go once it opens okay so I'm
going to go to google.com
so those are the two arguments uh which
I have passed right it should open in
the incognito mode and it should open
this URL right and let's go ahead and
run this
so as you can see the test has passed
and Google
.com is opened in Chrome in Incognito
mode okay
so that's how powerful this particular
t-box module is it can open any
particular application with parameters
or with arguments or even if it's a
username and password protected
application okay
now um coming to our last module which
we are going to look in this particular
session
is for timing okay so some modules which
are related to timing and I'm going to
add here a test case called start timer
right and then I am going to add in the
test case called stop timer
okay and what I'm going to do is I am
going to
bring in this particular uh
start Chrome right so let's actually
rename this
and this one is for notepad right so
start
Notepad
okay um so I'm going to add in the test
case here called uh open browser
right and I'm going to put it between
the start timer and the stop timer and
then I'm also going to copy this step
into the open browser test case right so
it's basically going to do the same
thing it's going to open the Chrome
browser but what I will get here is I
will get
um the time it takes to execute this
particular step okay
how we can do that uh we will add a
module here called The Box
start timer
okay
and here we need to provide ID which is
just nothing but the name of that
particular timer so I will say it is a
timer one okay
and the same thing here but we will have
a different t-box module so stop timer
and we'll be using the same ID here so
that this runs and calculates how much
time it is taking
right in terms of the timer running for
this particular test case
so we have got the start timer and stop
timer and let's go ahead and run this
whole folder
okay just executed now and in the
results you can now see that the log
info it has got a start timer which was
started okay
um the application was launched as
expected but in the stop timer you will
also find something called measured
value okay and that's the time it took
to execute this particular test step
which is in between these two timers and
that was 28 milliseconds okay
so it's quite useful if you want to know
how much a particular step uh is taking
to execute right and what also you can
do in the stop timer is you can put a
maximum duration
so this could be useful in doing a
performance test for your uh testing
right so if that particular step or a
particular test case is not completing
in that particular time then you can
mark it as failed right it did not uh
meet up to the performance expectations
of the particular test okay
so what I can do here is I can put a
maximum duration of just 10 milliseconds
and put a verify action mode and when I
execute this again
okay so this time around it's going to
fail uh because the verification field
okay and you can see in the stop timer
it is saying that the verification is
filled expected value was less than 10
seconds uh actually took 43 seconds
so it's basically a performance check or
a performance test right which you can
perform using this uh two t-box modules
uh start timer and start stop timer
okay so these are um all the commonly
used t-box modules uh which are generic
in terms of how you can do different
operations on files folders uh on your
applications starting and stopping and
also some performance tests
now there are many other modules which
are present uh in the standard subset
but these are the most commonly used
okay so that's all for this session uh
which covered the key box automation
modules